Register of the Allan E. Goodman papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1947-1975 (Boxes 26-37)
  - Turley, William S., "Army, Party and Society in the Democratic Republic of Vietnam: Civil-Military Relations in a Mass-Mobilization System," Ph.D. dissertation, University of Washington, 1972
  - Turley, William S., "The Political Role and Character of the People's Army of Vietnam,", 1974
  - Van der Kroef, Justus M., "The Vietnam Cease-Fire: Problems of Regional Stability and Security in Southease Asia,", undated (Box 37)
  - "The Viet Cong 'Tet' Offensive (1968),", 1969
  - Warner, Geoffrey, "Dependence and Injustice in World Politics: The United States and the Fall of Diem,", undated
  - Warner, Geoffrey, "The 1954 Geneva Agreements: An Ambiguous Legacy,", 1974
  - West, F. J., "Pacification and Security in Vietnam,", 1968
  - Westmoreland, General W. C., speech at Tufts University, Medford, Massachusetts, 1973 December 12
  - "'What the Local Annamites Are Thinking': Americans and Vietnamese in China, 1942-1945,", undated
  - Wie, Thee Kian, "An Estimation of Gross Value Added of Commerce in the Province of South Sumatra in 1970,", 1972
  - Wie, Thee Kian, "An Estimation of Gross Value Added of the Agricultural Sector in the Province of South Sumatra in 1970,", 1972
  - Wie, Thee Kian, "An Estimation of Private Consumption in South Sumatra in 1970,", 1973
  - Wie, Thee Kian, "Revised Summary of Gross Provincial Product Estimation for the Province of South Sumatra,", 1970, 1972
  - Wie, Thee Kian, "South Sumatra's External Trade in 1970,", 1973
  - Willis, John, "Social Status and Casualty Rates,", 1973
  - Woodside, Alexander B., "Decolonization and Agricultural Reform in Northern Vietnam,", 1970
  - Zasloff, J. J., "Origins of the Insurgency in South Vietnam, 1954-1960: The Role of the Southern Vietminh Cadres,", 1968
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1967-1971 (Box 37)
  Correspondence, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent. See also 1975 Increment.
  - General (Box 37)
  - Bell, David V. J.
  - Bolton, Robert
  - Boyle, Monica
  - Brown, Fred
  - Bunker, Ambassador Ellsworth
  - Carter, Audra
  - Cochran, Samuel W.
  - Colby, Ambassador William
  - D'Arc, Christine
  - De, Congressman Dinh Van
  - Engle, James
  - Firfer, Alexander
  - Fishel, Wesley
  - Ginsburg, Norton
  - Green, Lia
  - Hartz, Louis
  - Herber, Robert C.
  - Herz, Martin
  - Hickey, Gerald
  - Hien, Nguyen Van
  - Hoeber, Francis P.
  - Holland, Lynwood M.
  - Hoselitz, Bert F.
  - Humphrey, Hubert H.
  - Huntington, Samuel P.
  - Iklé, Fred C.
  - Jacobini, H. B.
  - Junz, Alfred J.
  - Ke, Congressman Khieu Thien
  - King, John E.
  - Kistner, Rudolph
  - Leopold, Richard W.
  - Loc, Hoang Van
  - Luykx, Nicolaas G. M., II
  - MacDonald, D. G.
  - McNamara, F. Terrance
  - Manley, Mrs.
  - Mills, Hauthorne
  - Montgomery, John D.
  - Moore, Frederick
  - Moose, George
  - Murphy, James P.
  - Nelson, Courtney
  - Newman, Cynthia S.
  - Ng, Ricky
  - Osborn, James
  - Paige, Glenn D.
  - Pauker, Guy J.
  - Pennock, J. Roland
  - Phong, Congressman Tran Quy
  - Piper, Carol
  - Porter, D. Gareth
  - Quaid, Daniel L., Jr.
  - Rambo, A. Terry
  - Sacks, I. Milton
  - Senser, Robert A.
  - Sheen, R. H.
  - Shoup, Frederick
  - Shubert, Gustave H.
  - Silverman, Jerry M.
  - Sperling, Philip
  - Stewart, William A.
  - Sweet, Charles F.
  - Teare, Richard W.
  - Thomson, Charles A. H.
  - Thornburg, Sam C.
  - Timberg, Thomas
  - U.S. Government Printing Office
  - Wohlstetter, Roberta
  - Young, Kenneth T.
  - Zasloff, Joseph
  - Zerolis, John
  - Zupzick, Major Gene
- 1975 INCREMENT, 1956-1974 (Boxes 38-108)
  Materials added in September 1975.
  - SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1966-1974 (Boxes 38-51)
    Arranged alphabetically by author and under author by title.
    - Bell, David V. J. and Allan E. Goodman, "Vietnam and the American Revolution: Old Subject, New Lesson,", 1971 (Box 38)
    - Cohen, Saul B., Allan E. Goodman and Roger E. Kasperson, "A Comparative Analysis of the Impact of Rapid Urban Growth on Political Change," prospectus, undated
    - Ellegiers, Daniel and Allan E. Goodman, ed., "After the War: An International Assessment," proposal, 1973
    - Goodman, Allan E.
      - "After Detente," prospectus, undated
      - "After the War, What?,", 1971
      - "The American Scholar, 1966,", undated
      - "The American Scholar Reconsidered,", undated
      - "Anatomy of the October Proposal on Vietnam,", undated
      - "Bitter Dregs in Paris?,", undated
      - "The Case for a Cease-Fire in Vietnam,", undated
      - "The Causes and Consequences of Migration to Saigon, Vietnam,", 1973
      - "The Causes and Consequences of Migration to Saigon, Vietnam,", 1973 (Box 39)
      - "A Chance to End the War?,", undated
      - "Conflict and Accommodation within a Legislative Elite in South Vietnam,", 1971
      - "Correlates of Legislative Constituency Service in South Vietnam,", 1971
      - "Costs of Shuttle Diplomacy,", 1974
      - "The Demilitarization of a Polity: South Vietnam's Emerging Elite,", undated
      - "Detente: The Road Ahead,", 1974
      - "Deterrence or Defense?,", undated
      - "Diplomatic and Strategic Outcomes of the Conflict,", undated
      - "Dollars for North Vietnam?,", 1973
      - "The End of the War as a Setting for the Future Development of South Vietnam,", 1971
      - "Ending the Viet Nam Conflict: Expectations in Hanoi and Saigon,", 1972
      - "Every Detente Ends,", undated (Box 40)
      - "Fate of the POW's,", undated
      - "The Future of the War is the Future of the Peace in Vietnam,", 1971
      - "Government and the Countryside: Political Accommodations and South Vietnam's Communal Groups,", undated
      - "The Growth and Future Development of Metropolitan Saigon: An Application of the Fragment Hypothesis to the Study of Rapid Urban Growth," proposal, undated
      - "Is It Really Over?,", undated
      - "Is It Too Late for the U.S. to End the War?: The Case for a Cease-Fire in Vietnam,", 1972
      - "Is It Too Late to End the Vietnam War?,", undated
      - "Leaving the Future Up for Grabs: The Political Consequences of the Vietnam Cease-Fire,", 1973
      - "Legislative Contributions to National Integration: Constituency Service in Eight Changing Societies,", 1974
      - "Limited War,", undated (Box 41)
      - "Migrants and Natives: The Fragment in East Asian National Development,", undated
      - "The Next Round in Paris: More of the Same?,", undated
      - "Nixon vs. Congress,", 1973
      - "Notes on Hyakusho Ikki of the Tokugawa Period,", 1971
      - "Notes on Operationalizing the Political and Governmental Consequences of National Development Policies Affecting the Size, Growth, Location and/or Composition of Urban Populations,", undated
      - "Notes on the Administration of Elections in South Vietnam,", 1967
      - "Notes on the Research Process: Some Comments for Undergraduate Students Taking their First Seminar,", undated
      - "Obligations to God and the Leviathan, undated
      - "On the Need for SALT in the Fable,", undated
      - "The Partition of Vietnam and the Unfinished Revolution,", 1971
      - "Peace Hurdles in Vietnam,", undated
      - "The Political Consequences of Urban Development and Growth Strategies in Singapore,", undated
      - "The Political Consequences of Urban Growth Policies in Southeast Asia,", undated
      - "The Political Consequences of Urban Growth Policies in Southeast Asia,", undated (Box 42)
      - "The Political Implications of Rural Problems in South Vietnam: Creating Public Interests,", 1970
      - "The Political Implications of Urban Development in Southeast Asia: The 'Fragment' Hypothesis,", 1971
      - Politics in War: The Bases of Political Community in South Vietnam, 1970
        - General
        - Proposals
        - Outlines
        - Preface
        - Chapter 1, "Introduction: Political Community and Political Order in South Vietnam" (Box 43)
        - Chapter 2, "Government vs. Politics: Traditional Political Institutions and the Absence of Political Community in Vietnam"
        - Chapter 3, "Elections and Political Participation in South Vietnam"
        - Chapter 4, "Representation as Participation: Bases for Conflict and Accommodation in the Polity"
        - Chapter 5, "Government under the Second Republic: Consolidation vs. the Creation of Political Power" (Box 44)
        - Chapter 6, "The Executive versus the Legislature: Political Competition and Institutional Imperative"
        - Chapter 7, "Legislative Blocs as Political Participation: Doctrines of Political Organization and Competition in Transition"
        - Chater 8, "Creating Public Demands: Patterns of Deputy-Constituency Relations"
        - Chapter 8, "Creating Public Demands: Patterns of Deputy-Constituency Relations" (Box 45)
        - Chapter 9, "Constituency Service Work and the Creation of National Interests"
        - Chapter 10, "The Bases of Political Community in South Vietnam"
        - Bibliographic essay
        - Bibliography
        - Index
        - Completed draft (Box 46)
        - Galley proofs
        - Reviews
      - "Politics Up Close: A Handbook for Field Researchers," prospectus, undated (Box 47)
      - "Possibilities of an International Organizational Role in the Postwar Recovery and Development of North and South Vietnam,", undated
      - " The Prince, the Viet Cong and the Economy of Violence,", undated
      - "Problems and Possibilities of an International Organization Role in a Recovery and Development Program for North and South Vietnam: An Assessment of Alternative Political Outcomes,", 1971
      - "Public Funding Isn't Political Reform,", 1974
      - "The Real Poverty in Higher Education,", 1973
      - "A Reconsideration of Freedom and Ferment: A Study of Freedom of Speech and the Local Community,", undated
      - "Redeeming the American Pledge of Postwar Assistance for Vietnam,", undated
      - "Reforming Campaign Financing Is Not Reforming Politics,", undated
      - Reviews of Bannan, John F. and Rosemary S. Bannan, Law, Morality and Vietnam: The Peace Militants and the Courts, 1974
      - Review of Fitzgerald, C. P., The Southern Expansion of the Chinese People, 1972
      - Review of Gamer, Robert E., The Politics of Urban Development in Singapore, 1972
      - Review of Heine-Geldern, Robert, "Conceptions of State and Kingship in Southeast Asia,", undated
      - Review of Hosmer, Stephen T., Viet Cong Repression and Its Implications for the Future, and Piero Gheddo, The Cross and the Bo-Tree: Catholics and Buddhists in Vietnam, 1974
      - Review of Huntington, Samuel P., Political Order in Changing Societies, undated
      - Review of Joint Development Group, The Postwar Development of the Republic of Vietnam: Policies and Programs, 1971
      - Review of Kaplan, Marshall, Urban Planning in the 1960's: A Design for Irrelevancy, undated
      - Review of Kaplan, Morton A., Abram Chayes, G. Warren Nutter, Paul C. Warnke, John P. Roche and Clayton Fritchey, Vietnam Settlement: Why 1973, Not 1969?
      - Review of McGee, T. C., The Urbanization Process in the Third World: Explorations in Search of a Theory, undated
      - Review of Moore, John Norton, Law and the Indochina War, 1973
      - Review of Penniman, Howard, Elections in South Vietnam, 1973
      - Review of The Pentagon Papers, undated
      - Review of Pye, Lucian W., Politics, Personality, and Nation Building: Burma's Search for Identity, undated
      - Reviews of Race, Jeffrey, War Comes to Long An: Revolutionary Conflict in a Vietnamese Province, and F. J. West, Jr., The Village, undated
      - Review of Randle, Robert F., Geneva, 1954: The Settlement of the Indochinese War, 1970
      - Reviews of Ryan, Byrce, Caste in Modern Ceylon: The Sinhalese System in Transition, and Marshall R. Singer, The Emerging Elite: A Study of Political Leadership in Ceylon, undated
      - Review of Sihanouk, Norodom, My War with the C.I.A., 1973
      - Review of Skinner, G. William, "The Chinese Minority,", undated
      - Review of Wilson, Peter J., A Malay Village and Malaysia: Social Values and Rural Development, undated
      - "The Search for Instability,", undated (Box 48)
      - "The 'Silent Majority' Is Wrong: The Future of the War Is the Future of the Peace in Vietnam,", undated
      - "Some Thoughts about How to Get a Job at Any Place Other than Harvard,", undated
      - "The Sources of Public Policy: A Case Study of Urban Development Policy in Korea,", undated
      - "South Vietnam: Neither War nor Peace,", 1970
      - "South Vietnam and the New Security,", undated
      - "The Spirit of '76,", undated
      - "The Subtle Crisis: Recommended Structure and Guidelines for a Marine Corps Integrated Information System,", undated
      - "Systems Approaches to Technical Cooperation: The Role of Development Administration,", 1969
      - "Toward a Geography of Political Participation,", undated
      - "Toward the Foundations of a Theory of Administrative Design,", 1966
      - "U.S. Development Assistance in the Insurgency Environment: Gulliver's Coming Out,", 1972
      - "United States Development Assistance in the Insurgency Environment: An Example of Why Foreign Aid Should Become Foreign Policy,", undated
      - "Urbanization and Political Change: In Search of Asia's Urban Revolution," prospectus, undated
      - "The Vice Presidency: Succession Is Too Much,", undated
      - "Vietnam a Year Later,", 1974
      - "Vietnam and the Limits of Scholarly Intervention,", 1973
      - "Vietnam and the Thucydidean Syndrome,", undated
      - "The Vietnam Negotiations," proposal, undated (Box 49)
      - "The Votes Are In,", 1974
      - "Watergate and Foreign Policy: A Dissenting View,", 1973
      - "What Our Defense Budget Means,", undated
      - "What to Look for in the Coming South Vietnamese Elections: A Personal Assessment of Practical Politics,", undated
      - "What Went Wrong in Saigon?,", 1972
      - "What's Ahead for Indo-China?,", 1973
      - "Will Detente Last,", undated
      - "Will the Vietnam War End?,", undated
      - "With Peace at Hand,", 1973
      - Untitled, undated
    - Goodman, Allan E. and Lawrence M. Franks, "Between War and Peace: A Profile of Migrants to Saigon,", undated
    - Goodman, Allan E., Randolph Harris and John C. Wood, "South Vietnam and the Politics of Self-Support,", 1971
    - Henderson, Gregory and Allan E. Goodman, "Korea and Vietnam: A Comparison,", 1971
    - Krefetz, Sharon Perlman and Allan E. Goodman, "Participation for What or for Whom?: Some Considerations for Research,", 1973
    - Rasmussen, Knud and Allan E. Goodman, letter to the editor, New York Times and Worcester Telegram and Gazette, 1971 March 5
    - Zasloff, Joseph J. and Allan E. Goodman, ed., Indochina in Conflict: A Political Assessment, 1971-1972 (Box 50)
      Contains revised versions of papers presented at the Vietnam, Laos, and Cambodia Panel Meeting for the Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group in New York City, May 7-8, 1971.
      - Vietnam, Laos, and Cambodia Panel Meeting, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, New York City, 1971 May 1971
        - Reports of proceedings
        - Tests of papers presented
      - General
      - Summary of contents and abstract
      - Introduction
      - Chapter 1, Elizabeth Pond, "South Vietnamese Politics and the American Withdrawal"
      - Chapter 2, William S. Turley, "The DRV since the Death of Ho Chi Minh: The Politics of a Revolution in Transition"
      - Chapter 3, Donald Lancaster, "The Decline of Prince Sihanouk's Regime" (Box 51)
      - Chapter 4, Milton Osborne, "Effacing the 'God-King': Internal Developments in Cambodia since March 1970"
      - Chapter 5, Arthur Dommen, "Lao Politics under Prince Souvanna Phouma"
      - Chapter 6, Konrad Kellen, "1971 and Beyond: The View from Hanoi"
      - Chapter 7, Joseph J. Zasloff, "Leadership and Organization of the Pathet Lao"
      - Chapter 8, David E. Brown, "Exporting Insurgency: The Communists in Cambodia"
      - Chapter 9, Melvin Gurtov, "Indochina in North Vietnamese Strategy"
      - Chapter 10, Bernard K. Gordon, "Cambodia's Foreign Relations: Sihanouk and After"
      - Chapter 11, Robert H. Johnson, "The Nixon Doctrine and the New Policy Environment"
      - Chapter 12, MacAlister Brown, "The Impact of the Indochina Involvement on American Political Institutions"
      - Index
      - Galley proofs
      - Reviews
  - SUBJECT FILE, 1956-1974 (Boxes 52-96)
    Unpublished writings, correspondence, notes, clippings, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Aden, insurgency (Box 52)
    - Afghanistan, politics
    - Africa
      - Christianity
      - Coups
      - Politics
    - Agriculture
      - Collectivization
      - "Green Revolution"
    - Alienation, Yin, Robert K. and William A. Lucas, "Decentralization and Alienation,", 1973
    - American Revolution
      - General
      - Bell, David V. J.
        - "The American Revolution and the Founding of English Canada,", 1971
        - "Colony or Nation?: Whig and Tory and the Debate on the American Revolution,", 1969
        - "The Loyalists: The First American Expatriates,", 1971
        - "Nation and Non-Nation: A New Analysis of Loyalists and the American Revolution,", 1969
        - "Nationalism and the American Revolution,", 1969
      - "English Society and the American Revolution,", undated
      - "Parliament and the American Revolution,", undated
    - Argentina, politics
    - Arms trade, international
    - Asian Development Bank
      - Black, Eugene R., statement before U.S. Senate Foreign Relations Committee, 1967 October 3
      - U.S. National Advisory Council on International Monetary and Financial Policies, "Special Funds of the Asian Development Bank,", 1967
    - Australia
      - Economy
      - Foreign policy
      - Politics
    - Bangladesh
    - Bhumibol Adulyadej, King
    - Biographical
    - Bolivia
      - Insurgency
      - Politics
    - Borneo
    - Boumedienne, Houari
    - Boundaries. U.S. Department of State Geographer, "Burma-Laos Boundary,", 1964
    - Brazil
      - Bureaucracy
      - Military in politics
    - Brezhnev, Leonid I.
    - Buddhism
    - Bunker, Ambassador Ellsworth
    - Bureaucracy
      - General. Bell, David V. J., "The Growth and Development of Responsible Bureaucracy in Canada and the United States,", 1970
      - Bibliography
    - Burma
      - General
      - Buddhism
      - Culture
      - Economy
      - Insurgency
      - Politics
    - Cambodia
      - General
      - Coup, 1970 March
      - Elections
      - Foreign policy
        - General
        - Heng, Cheng, speech at the National Press Club, Washington, D.C., 1970 October 21
        - Voeunsai, Ambassador Sonn, speech at the University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, 1971 February 12
      - Politics
      - Sihanouk, Prince Norodom, regime
    - Canada, political community. Bell, David V. J., "Regionalism in the Canadian Community,", 1971
    - Chile, politics
    - China (Box 53)
      - Bibliography
      - Communism
      - Constitutions
      - "Cultural Revolution"
      - Defense policy
        - General
        - Heinlein, Joseph J., Jr., "China's Force Posture: Factors in the Policy Process,", 1972
        - Hsieh, Alice L., review of Cheng, Chester, ed., The Politics of the Chinese Red Army, 1966
        - Powell, Ralph L., "The Military Doctrines of the People's Republic of China,", undated
      - Foreign policy
        - General
        - Gurtov, Melvin, "'Style' in the Politics and Foreign Policy of Communist China,", 1968
      - Foreign policy in Vietnam
        - General
        - Mozingo, D. P. and T. W. Robinson, "Lin Piao on 'People's War': China Takes a Second Look at Vietnam,", 1965
      - History
      - Nationalism, Hien, Nguyen Van, "China: Patterns of Response to External Threat,", 1973
      - Politics, Hsieh, Alice Langley, "Some Thoughts on the Decisionmaking Hierarchy and Process in Crisis Situations in Communist China: 1977,", 1968
      - Relations with Burma
      - Relations with Cambodia
      - Relations with Laos
      - Relations with Malaysia
      - Relations with North Vietnam
      - Relations with Taiwan
      - Relations with Thailand
      - Rural development, New England China Seminar, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1963 October 17
    - Chinese in Indonesia
    - Chinese in Thailand
    - Communications and national development Bagdikian, Ben H., "Communications and Change, 1848 and 1968,"
    - Comparative politics
      - General
      - Form, William H., "Field Politics in Comparative Research: The Politics of Distrust,", undated
      - Janda, Kenneth, "Variations in the Dimensions of Political Parties across Nations,", 1970
      - Bibliography, Schneider, William, comp., "Political Development: Area and Country Studies (Central and South America, Asia, Middle East and North Africa, Sub-Saharan Africa),", 1968
    - Computer programs. Werbos, Paul, "Two Computer Programs to Help with Social Science Models,", 1968 (Box 54)
    - Conservatism
    - Constitutionalism
    - Counterinsurgency
      - General
      - Kecskemiti, P., "Insurgency as a Strategic Problem,", 1967
      - Menges, Constantine, "Democratic Revolutionary Insurgency as an Alternative Strategy,", 1968
      - Pauker, Guy J., "Notes on Non-Military Measures in Control of Insurgency,", 1962
      - U.S. Marine Corps, "Counterinsurgency Operations,", 1967
      - Wolf, Charles, Jr., "Insurgency and Counterinsurgency: New Myths and Old Realities,", 1965
    - Counterinsurgency and air power, Peterson, A. H., G. Reinhardt and E. E. Conger, ed., "Symposium on the Role of Air Power in Counterinsurgency and Unconventional Warfare"
      - "Allied Resistance to the Japanese on Luzon, World II,", 1963
      - "Chindit Operations in Burma,", 1963
      - "The Malayan Emergency,", 1963
      - "The Philippine Huk Campaign,", 1963
    - Cuba, Castro regime
    - Cultural pluralism
    - Dalat, South Vietnam
    - Dan, Dr. Phan Quang
    - Dat, Senator Truong Tien
    - Debray, Regis
    - Defense policies
      - General
      - Alcala, Raoul H., "Threats: Basic Rationales for Military Institutions,", undated
      - Arad, Uzi, William Bacchus, Edward Gonzalez and Harvey Starr, "Relevance Potentialities of National Security Research: Social Science or Policy Science: A Design for Inquiry,", undated
      - Butterworth, Robert, "Deep Threat: Systemic Considerations in National Security Policy,", 1973
      - Wolfowitz, Paul, "The Pot and the Kettle, or Rationality within Reason: Mr. Green's Deadly Logic,", undated
      - Yanarella, Ernest J., "Arms and Impotence: The Concepts of Violence, Rationality and Control in the Strategic Analyses of T. C. Schelling,", undated
    - Demography (Box 55)
    - Diem, Ngo Dinh
    - Disarmament
      - General
      - Fairbanks, Charles, "Arms Race,", undated
      - Herrmann, Rene, "Notes on Arms Races,", undated
      - Logsdon, John M., "Future Issues in Strategy and Arms Control: Bureaucratic Politics or Rational Choices?,", undated
      - Steiner, Arthur, "Minimum Deterrence as a Step Toward Disarmament,", undated
      - "The Technological Environment of US-SU Antagonism and the Arms Race Concept,", undated
      - Yanarella, Ernest J., "The Technological Imperative and the Strategic Arms Race in the Sixties,", undated
    - Dzu, Truong Dinh
    - Economic theory
    - El Salvador, elections
    - Electoral systems
    - Energy crisis
    - Ethiopia, politics
    - Europe, defenses
      - General
      - U.S. Department of State, "United States Troop Levels in Europe,", 1973
    - European Economic Community
    - European Security Conference
    - Family
    - France
      - Defense policy